[{"id":"fuf-vpfj","version":"Pular Fuuta-Jallon New Testament","description":"Pular: Version Pular Fuuta-Jallon New Testament","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Pular","code":"fuf","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Guinea","code":"GN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Melva Wahl","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Version Pular Fuuta-Jallon","localVersionAbbreviation":"VPFJ"},{"id":"uk-внпу","version":"Biblica® Open New Ukrainian Translation 2022 (New Testament and Psalms)","description":"Ukrainian: Бібліка ® Відкрита Новий Переклад Українською (New Testament+)","scope":"New Testament+","language":{"name":"Ukrainian","code":"ukr","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Ukraine","code":"UA"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Cyrillic","archivist":"Kent Spielmann","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Бібліка ® Відкрита Новий Переклад Українською","localVersionAbbreviation":"ВНПУ"},{"id":"grc-grcbrent","version":"Brenton Greek Text","description":"Greek, Ancient: μετάφραση των εβδομήκοντα (Old Testament + Deuterocanon)","scope":"Old Testament + Deuterocanon","language":{"name":"Greek, Ancient","code":"grc","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Greece","code":"GR"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Greek","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"μετάφραση των εβδομήκοντα","localVersionAbbreviation":"GRCBRENT"},{"id":"grc-srgnt","version":"Solid Rock Greek New Testament, Scholar's Edition","description":"Greek, Ancient: Solid Rock Greek New Testament, Scholar's Edition (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Greek, Ancient","code":"grc","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States of America","code":"US"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Greek","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Solid Rock Greek New Testament, Scholar's Edition","localVersionAbbreviation":"SRGNT"},{"id":"xnj-nb2020","version":"Ngoni Bible Version Translation Project","description":"Ngoni: Ngoni Bible Version Translation Project","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Ngoni (Tanzania)","code":"xnj","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania, United Republic of","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Gladys Grasso","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Ngoni Bible Version Translation Project","localVersionAbbreviation":"NB2020"},{"id":"anh-nendnp03","version":"Nend Portions - Mark","description":"Mark in Nend","scope":"Portions","language":{"name":"Nend","code":"anh","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Papua New Guinea","code":"PG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Mike Herchenroeder","copyright":"","localVersionName":"MAK Yakŋ Ohɨrand Ya Imbɨr Makɨv Mpamar","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"kdc-kutub","version":"Kutu Bible Version Translation Project","description":"Kutu: Biblia Kikutu (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Kutu","code":"kdc","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania, United Republic of","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblia Kikutu","localVersionAbbreviation":"KutuB"},{"id":"kbq-kbqbible","version":"AKBQ CChecked orginal with alphabet and revision changes","description":"Kamano: Anumzamofo Routage Avantafere (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Kamano","code":"kbq","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Papua New Guinea","code":"PG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"KMPJ","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Anumzamofo Routage Avantafere","localVersionAbbreviation":"KBQBible"},{"id":"es-pddpt","version":"Palabra de Dios para ti","description":"A Bible translation in modern Spanish","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Spanish","code":"spa","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Venezuela, Bolivarian Republic ofColombiaEcuadorBolivia, Plurinational State ofPeruArgentinaBrazilParaguayUruguayEl SalvadorNicaraguaDominican RepublicCubaHondurasGuatemalaPanamaMexicoChileSpain","code":"VECOECBOPEARBRPYUYSVNIDOCUHNGTPAMXCLES"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Palabra de Dios para ti","localVersionAbbreviation":"PdDpt"},{"id":"he-wlc","version":"Westminster Leningrad Codex","description":"Hebrew: Westminster Leningrad Codex","scope":"Old Testament","language":{"name":"Hebrew","code":"heb","level":"Literary"},"country":{"name":"Unspecific","code":"ZZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Hebrew","archivist":"Emma Canales","copyright":"","localVersionName":"United Bible Societies","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"urw-sobp15","version":"Sob Jonah and Luke","description":"Sop: Profet Yonab Budi / Dora Nama Lukde Feiaga (Portions)","scope":"Portions","language":{"name":"Sop","code":"urw","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Papua New Guinea","code":"PG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Mike Herchenroeder","copyright":"JonahLuke","localVersionName":"Profet Yonab Budi / Dora Nama Lukde Feiaga","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"yap-yap","version":"Yapese Bible","description":"The Holy Bible in the Yapese language of Micronesia","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Yapese","code":"yap","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Micronesia, Federated States of","code":"FM"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Bible Ni Thothup","localVersionAbbreviation":"YAP"},{"id":"gai-mbkamnt","version":"Mborena Kam NT for DBL","description":"New Testament in Mborena Kam language","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Borei","code":"gai","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Papua New Guinea","code":"PG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Mike Herchenroeder","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Raraŋ Aetaniacna Kam Wembaŋ Laŋ","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"kde-makonde","version":"Makonde Bible Version","description":"Makonde: Lilailano Lyahambi Lya Nnungu Kwa Vanu Vammalele (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Makonde","code":"kde","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania, United Republic of","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Lilailano Lyahambi Lya Nnungu Kwa Vanu Vammalele","localVersionAbbreviation":"Makonde"},{"id":"en-t4t","version":"Translation for Translators [eng] USA","description":"An English translation of the Holy Bible that makes implicit information explicit","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States of America","code":"US"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"The Holy Bible: A Translation for Translators","localVersionAbbreviation":"T4T"},{"id":"nl-nld1939","version":"De Heilige Schrift, Petrus Canisiusvertaling, 1939 [nld] Netherlands","description":"The Holy Bible with Deuterocanon in the Dutch language, Petrus Canisiusvertaling, 1939","scope":"Bible with Deuterocanon","language":{"name":"Dutch","code":"nld","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Netherlands","code":"NL"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Johnson (PNG Scriptures)","copyright":"","localVersionName":"De Heilige Schrift, Petrus Canisiusvertaling, 1939","localVersionAbbreviation":"NLD1939"},{"id":"pt-tftp","version":"Translation for Translators in Portuguese","description":"Portuguese: A Bíblia Sagrada, Tradução para Tradutores (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Portuguese","code":"por","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Brazil","code":"BR"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Johnson (PNG Scriptures)","copyright":"","localVersionName":"A Bíblia Sagrada, Tradução para Tradutores","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"sa-Beng-IN-laukika-sanbn","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Bengali Script (সত্যবেদঃ।)","description":"Sanskrit: Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Bengali Script (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Bengali","script":"Bengali","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Bengali Script","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANBN"},{"id":"sa-Beng-IN-laukika-sanas","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Assamese Script (সত্যৱেদঃ।)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Assamese Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Bengali","script":"Bengali","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Assamese Script","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANAS"},{"id":"sa-Zzzz-MM-laukika-sanbu","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Burmese Script (သတျဝေဒး၊)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Burmese Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Code for uncoded script","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"SanskritBible.in","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANBU"},{"id":"sa-Latn-001-laukika-sanco","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Cologne Script (satyavEdaH|)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Cologne Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Latin","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Cologne Script","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANCO"},{"id":"sa-Gujr-IN-laukika-sangj","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Gujarati Script (સત્યવેદઃ।)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Gujarati Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Gujarati","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Gujarati Script","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANGJ"},{"id":"sa-Knda-IN-laukika-sanka","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Kannada Script (ಸತ್ಯವೇದಃ।)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Kannada Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Kannada","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Kannada Script","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANKA"},{"id":"sa-Latn-001-laukika-sanhk","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Harvard-Kyoto Script (satyavedaH|)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Harvard-Kyoto Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Latin","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Harvard-Kyoto Script","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"sa-Latn-001-laukika-sanit","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in ITRANS Script (satyavedaH|)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in ITRANS Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Latin","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in ITRANS Script","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANIT"},{"id":"sa-Zzzz-KH-laukika-sankh","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Khmer Script (សត្យវេទះ។)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Khmer Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"Cambodia","code":"KH"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Code for uncoded script","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Khmer Script","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANKH"},{"id":"sa-Mlym-IN-laukika-sanml","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Malayalam Script (സത്യവേദഃ।)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Malayalam Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Malayalam","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"SanskritBible.in","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANML"},{"id":"sa-Orya-IN-laukika-sanor","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Oriya Script (ସତ୍ୟୱେଦଃ।)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Oriya Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Oriya","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"0 Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Oriya Script (ସତ୍ୟୱେଦଃ।)","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANOR"},{"id":"sa-Zzzz-IN-laukika-sanpn","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Punjabi Script (ਸਤ੍ਯਵੇਦਃ।)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Punjabi Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Code for uncoded script","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"0 Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Punjabi Script (ਸਤ੍ਯਵੇਦਃ।)","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANPN"},{"id":"sa-Zzzz-LK-laukika-sansi","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Sinhala Script (සත්‍යවේදඃ।)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Sinhala Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"Sri Lanka","code":"LK"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Code for uncoded script","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"SanskritBible.in","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANSI"},{"id":"sa-Telu-IN-laukika-sante","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Telugu Script (సత్యవేదః।)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Telugu Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Telugu","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"SanskritBible.in","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANTE"},{"id":"sa-Tibt-CN-laukika-santi","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Tibetan Script (སཏྱཝེདཿ།)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Tibetan Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"China","code":"CN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Tibetan","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"SanskritBible.in","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANTI"},{"id":"sa-Latn-001-laukika-sania","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in IAST Script (satyavedaḥ|)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in IAST Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Latin","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"SanskritBible.in","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANIA"},{"id":"sa-Latn-001-laukika-sanis","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in ISO Script (satyavēdaḥ|)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in ISO Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Latin","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"SanskritBible.in","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANIS"},{"id":"sa-Deva-IN-laukika-san-dn","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Devanagari Script (सत्यवेदः।)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Devanagari Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"SanskritBible.in","localVersionAbbreviation":"SAN-DN"},{"id":"sa-Arab-IN-laukika-sanur","version":"Sanskrit Bible (NT) in Urdu Script (سَتْیَویدَح۔)","description":"New Testament in Sanskrit Language; printed in Urdu Script","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Sanskrit","code":"san","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Roman","script":"Arabic","archivist":"Manu Mathew Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"SanskritBible.in","localVersionAbbreviation":"SANUR"},{"id":"en-ojps","version":"Old JPS TaNaKH","description":"The Jewish Bible (Old Testament) in English, old JPS version of 1917","scope":"Old Testament","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States","code":"US"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Johnson (PNG Scriptures)","copyright":"","localVersionName":"JPS TaNaKH 1917","localVersionAbbreviation":"OJPS"},{"id":"pl-ubg","version":"UWSPÓŁCZEŚNIONA BIBLIA GDAŃSKA [pol]","description":"The Holy Bible in the Polish language, Updated Biblia Gdansk translation","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Polish","code":"pol","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Poland","code":"PL"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Johnson (PNG Scriptures)","copyright":"","localVersionName":"UWSPÓŁCZEŚNIONA BIBLIA GDAŃSKA","localVersionAbbreviation":"UBG"},{"id":"en-engbrent","version":"Brenton English Septuagint","description":"Translation of the Greek Septuagint into English by Sir Lancelot Charles Lee Brenton","scope":"Old Testament + Deuterocanon","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United KingdomUnited States","code":"GBUS"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Johnson (PNG Scriptures)","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Brenton English Septuagint","localVersionAbbreviation":"engbrent"},{"id":"en-oke","version":"Targum Onkelos Etheridge","description":"Public domain","scope":"Portions","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Unspecific","code":"ZZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Targum Onkelos Etheridge","localVersionAbbreviation":"OKE"},{"id":"sr-Latn-srp1865","version":"Serbian Bible (Vuk Karadžić, Đura Daničić) [srp] Serbia","description":"The Holy Bible in Serbian (Latin alphabet), translated by Vuk Karadžić and Đura Daničić","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Serbian","code":"srp","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Serbia","code":"RS"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Johnson (PNG Scriptures)","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Sveta Biblija","localVersionAbbreviation":"SRP1865"},{"id":"en-gnv","version":"Geneva Bible 1599 [eng] Old English","description":"The Geneva Bible in Old English of 1599","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United Kingdom","code":"GB"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Johnson (PNG Scriptures)","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Geneva Bible","localVersionAbbreviation":"GNV"},{"id":"spm-akg-mkac","version":"Akukem Portions for DBL","description":"Published Mark & Acts","scope":"Portions","language":{"name":"Akukem","code":"spm","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Papua New Guinea","code":"PG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Mike Herchenroeder","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Mak Osɨrisira Akaman Aghuuŋ ko Iesusɨm Mbɨsevisir Gumasi","localVersionAbbreviation":"Akg-MkAc"},{"id":"mgw-matumbi","version":"Matumbi Bible Version","description":"Matumbi: Injili ya Yesu (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Matumbi","code":"mgw","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania, United Republic of","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Injili ya Yesu","localVersionAbbreviation":"Matumbi"},{"id":"mgc-mkd","version":"Morokodo","description":"Morokodo: Morokodo Portions","scope":"Portions","language":{"name":"Morokodo","code":"mgc","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"South Sudan","code":"SS"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Melva Wahl","copyright":"","localVersionName":"","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"be-BY-tarask-ббл","version":"Bible in belarusian","description":"Belarusan: Біблія (пераклад В.Сёмухі) (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Belarusian","code":"bel","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Belarus","code":"BY"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Cyrillic","archivist":"Mikalai Malashchonak","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Біблія (пераклад В.Сёмухі)","localVersionAbbreviation":"ББЛ"},{"id":"to-rwv","version":"Tongan Revised West Version","description":"Tongan: KO E TOHI TAPU KĀTOA (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Tonga (Tonga Islands)","code":"ton","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tonga","code":"TO"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Johnson (PNG Scriptures)","copyright":"","localVersionName":"KO E TOHI TAPU KĀTOA","localVersionAbbreviation":"RWV"},{"id":"de-tkw","version":"Textbibel von Kautzsch und Weizsäcker [deu] German","description":"The Holy Bible in German, translation by Kautzsch und Weizsäcker 1906","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"German","code":"deu","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Germany","code":"DE"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Johnson (PNG Scriptures)","copyright":"PUBLIC DOMAIN","localVersionName":"Textbibel von Kautzsch und Weizsäcker","localVersionAbbreviation":"TKW"},{"id":"en-US-emtv","version":"English Majority Text Version","description":"English: English Majority Text Version (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States","code":"US"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"English Majority Text Version","localVersionAbbreviation":"EMTV"},{"id":"cs-bkr","version":"Czech Bible Kralická 1613 [ces] Czech Republic","description":"The Holy Bible in the Czech language from the last Kralická edition of 1613.","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Czech","code":"ces","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Czech Republic","code":"CZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"PUBLIC DOMAIN","localVersionName":"Bible Kralická 1613","localVersionAbbreviation":"BKR"},{"id":"en-lsv","version":"Literal Standard Version","description":"English: Literal Standard Version (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States of AmericaUnited Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern IrelandCanadaAustraliaSouth AfricaNew Zealand","code":"USGBCAAUZANZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Gary Ray","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Literal Standard Version","localVersionAbbreviation":"LSV"},{"id":"de-luther1912","version":"Die Heilige Bibel übersetzt von Martin Luther 1912 mit Strongs Zahlen","description":"1912 Luther Bible with Strong's numbers","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"German, Standard","code":"deu","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"GermanyAustriaSwitzerland","code":"DEATCH"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"1912 Lutherbibel mit Strongs Zahlen","localVersionAbbreviation":"Luther1912"},{"id":"it-db1885","version":"Italian: Diodati Bible 1885","description":"Italian: Diodati Bible 1885","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Italian","code":"ita","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Italy","code":"IT"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Gladys Grasso","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Diodati Bibbia 1885","localVersionAbbreviation":"DB1885"},{"id":"grc-f35","version":"The Greek New Testament According to Family 35, Third Edition","description":"Greek, Ancient: The Greek New Testament According to Family 35 (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Greek, Ancient","code":"grc","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Unspecific","code":"ZZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Greek","archivist":"Michael Paul Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"The Greek New Testament According to Family 35","localVersionAbbreviation":"F35"},{"id":"en-US-f35","version":"The English New Testament According to Family 35","description":"English: The English New Testament According to Family 35 (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Unspecific","code":"ZZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Paul Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"The English New Testament According to Family 35","localVersionAbbreviation":"F35"},{"id":"en-US-kjvcpb","version":"The Cambridge Paragraph Bible of the Authorized English Version","description":"English: The Cambridge Paragraph Bible of the Authorized English Version (Bible with Deuterocanon)","scope":"Bible with Deuterocanon","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States","code":"US"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Paul Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"The Cambridge Paragraph Bible of the Authorized English Version","localVersionAbbreviation":"KJVCPB"},{"id":"en-rv","version":"Revised Version 1885","description":"Revision of the King James Version completed in 1885","scope":"Bible with Deuterocanon","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland","code":"GB"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"KMPJ","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Revised Version","localVersionAbbreviation":"RV"},{"id":"grc-byz1904","version":"1904 Patriarchal Greek New Testament (with 20 corrections from later editions)","description":"Greek, Ancient: Η Καινή Διαθήκη (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Greek, Ancient","code":"grc","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Greece","code":"GR"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Greek","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Η Καινή Διαθήκη","localVersionAbbreviation":"BYZ1904"},{"id":"bfz-Deva-IN-bghnt","version":"Baghlayani NT","description":"Bible in Baghlayani language","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Pahari, Mahasu","code":"bfz","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Hanok Kurian","copyright":"","localVersionName":"बघल्याणी  नवां विधान","localVersionAbbreviation":"BGHNT"},{"id":"mdy-Ethi-mnt","version":"Maale New Testament","description":"MALE: Maale New Testament","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Male (Ethiopia)","code":"mdy","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Ethiopia","code":"ET"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Ethiopic","archivist":"Aline Camus","copyright":"","localVersionName":"The Word for the World International","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"mwe-shimwela","version":"Mwera Bible Version","description":"Mwera: Malagano ga Ambi (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Mwera","code":"mwe","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania, United Republic of","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Malagano ga Ambi","localVersionAbbreviation":"Shimwela"},{"id":"grc-grctr","version":"Greek Textus Receptus, including the variants of Beza, Elzevir, Erasmus, Scrivener, and Stephanus","description":"Greek, Ancient: Η Καινή Διαθήκη (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Greek, Ancient","code":"grc","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Unspecific","code":"ZZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Greek","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Η Καινή Διαθήκη","localVersionAbbreviation":"GRCTR"},{"id":"en-US-lxxup","version":"Brenton English Septuagint (Updated Spelling and Formatting)","description":"English: Brenton English Septuagint (Updated Spelling and Formatting) (Old Testament + Deuterocanon)","scope":"Old Testament + Deuterocanon","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Unspecific","code":"ZZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Paul Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Brenton English Septuagint (Updated Spelling and Formatting)","localVersionAbbreviation":"LXXup"},{"id":"en-fbv","version":"Free Bible Version","description":"Free Bible Version","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States of America","code":"US"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Jonathan Gallagher","copyright":"Version 4.1.","localVersionName":"Free Bible Version","localVersionAbbreviation":"FBV"},{"id":"vid-chividunda","version":"Vidunda Bible Version","description":"Ilagano Linyale kwa Wanhu Weng'ha na Ilagano lya Katali","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Vidunda","code":"vid","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania, United Republic of","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Ilagano lya Katali, Ilagano Linyale kwa Wanhu Weng’ha","localVersionAbbreviation":"Chividunda"},{"id":"es-rv09","version":"Reina Valera 1909","description":"Español: Reina Valera 1909","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Spanish","code":"spa","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Unspecific","code":"ZZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Emma Canales","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Reina Valera 1909","localVersionAbbreviation":"RV09"},{"id":"pes-opcb","version":"Biblica® Open Persian Contemporary Bible 2022","description":"Persian, Iranian: Biblica® Open Persian Contemporary Bible 2022 (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Persian, Iranian","code":"pes","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Iran, Islamic Republic of","code":"IR"},"numeralSystem":"Farsi","script":"Arabic","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Open Persian Contemporary Bible 2022","localVersionAbbreviation":"OPCB"},{"id":"de-elo","version":"German Unrevised Elberfelder Bible [deu] Germany","description":"German Unrevised Elberfelder Bible 1905","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"German, Standard","code":"deu","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"GermanyAustria","code":"DEAT"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Paul Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Darby Unrevidierte Elberfelder 1905","localVersionAbbreviation":"ELO"},{"id":"bgc-Deva-IN-bgcnt","version":"Haryanvi Bible","description":"Bible in Haryanvi Language (bgc)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Haryanvi","code":"bgc","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Hanok Kurian","copyright":"","localVersionName":"हरियाणवी बाइबिल","localVersionAbbreviation":"BGCNT"},{"id":"en-dra","version":"Duay-Rheims American Edition  1899 [eng] USA","description":"Duay-Rheims translation of the Latin Vulgate into American English, 1899","scope":"Bible with Deuterocanon","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Literary"},"country":{"name":"United States","code":"US"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Paul Johnson","copyright":"PUBLIC DOMAIN","localVersionName":"Douay-Rheims American 1899","localVersionAbbreviation":"DRA"},{"id":"tvt-tut","version":"Tutsa: Bible Translation 1st Edition","description":"Tutsa Naga first Bible translation based on TEV (Good News)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Tutsa Naga","code":"tvt","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Gladys Grasso","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Esa Leedap Ena Banlam","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"tgj-tag","version":"Tagin: Bible Translation 1st Edition","description":"Tagin first Bible translation based on TEV (Good News)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Tagin","code":"tgj","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Gladys Grasso","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ANWNV GAMLV","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"sby-sbt","version":"SOLI BIBLE TRANSLATION","description":"Soli: Soli New Testament","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Soli","code":"sby","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"Zambia","code":"ZM"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Gladys Grasso","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Soli New Testament","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"dwr-Latn-dwnt","version":"Dawro New Testament","description":"Dawro: Dawro New Testament","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Dawro","code":"dwr","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"Ethiopia","code":"ET"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Gladys Grasso","copyright":"","localVersionName":"The Word for the World International","localVersionAbbreviation":"DWNT"},{"id":"gmv-ggmnt","version":"Gamo Geesha Maxxafa New Testament","description":"Gamo: Gamo Geesha Maxxafa New Testament (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Gamo","code":"gmv","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"Ethiopia","code":"ET"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Gladys Grasso","copyright":"","localVersionName":"The Word for the World International","localVersionAbbreviation":"GGMNT"},{"id":"bdv-ntbpl20","version":"Bodo Parja: BOPO Bible","description":"Bodo Parja: BOPO Bible","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Bodo Parja","code":"bdv","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Oriya","archivist":"Gladys Grasso","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ସଃର୍ଗାର୍‌ ବାଟ୍‌ ନଃଉଁଆ ନିଅମ୍‌","localVersionAbbreviation":"NTBPL20"},{"id":"yao-ynt2018","version":"Yao Bible Version Translation Project","description":"Yao: Yao Bible Version Translation Project","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Yao","code":"yao","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania, United Republic of","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Gladys Grasso","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Lilangano lya Sambano","localVersionAbbreviation":"YNT2018"},{"id":"nnq-nnqnt","version":"Ngindo New Testament","description":"Ngindo: Ngindo New Testament New Testament","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Ngindo","code":"nnq","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Gladys Grasso","copyright":"","localVersionName":"The Word for the World International","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"gof-gofnt","version":"Gofa New Testament","description":"Gofa: Gofa New Testament (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Gofa","code":"gof","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"Ethiopia","code":"ET"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Gladys Grasso","copyright":"","localVersionName":"The Word for the World International","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"cwe-kwere","version":"Kwere Bible Version","description":"Kwere: Biblia Ching'hwele (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Kwere","code":"cwe","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania, United Republic of","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Melva Wahl","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblia Ching'hwele","localVersionAbbreviation":"Kwere"},{"id":"lbm-Deva-IN-ntlii20","version":"Lodhi New Testament","description":"Lodhi: परमेश्वर को सच्चो वचन (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Lodhi","code":"lbm","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Devanagari","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Chhotray Aind","copyright":"","localVersionName":"परमेश्वर को सच्चो वचन","localVersionAbbreviation":"NTLii20"},{"id":"nlx-ntnii2020","version":"Nahali New Testament","description":"Nahali: खेरलो वचन (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Nahali","code":"nlx","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Devanagari","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Chhotray Aind","copyright":"","localVersionName":"खेरलो वचन","localVersionAbbreviation":"NTNii2020"},{"id":"bpx-Deva-IN-ntppt2020","version":"Paliya New Testament","description":"Bareli, Palya: भगवान ना खरला बोल (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Bareli, Palya","code":"bpx","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Devanagari","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Chhotray Aind","copyright":"","localVersionName":"भगवान ना खरला बोल","localVersionAbbreviation":"NTPPt2020"},{"id":"hoy-Deva-IN-nthaa20","version":"Holiya  New Testament","description":"Holiya: परमेश्‍वर उन खरा वचन (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Holiya","code":"hoy","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Devanagari","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Chhotray Aind","copyright":"","localVersionName":"परमेश्‍वर उन खरा वचन","localVersionAbbreviation":"NTHaa20"},{"id":"kfc-Orya-034-x-konda-ntkoo20","version":"Konda Porja New Testament","description":"Konda-Dora: ମାପୁରୁଦି ସତ୍‌ ବାକ୍ୟ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Konda-Dora","code":"kfc","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Oriya","script":"Oriya","archivist":"Chhotray Aind","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ମାପୁରୁଦି ସତ୍‌ ବାକ୍ୟ","localVersionAbbreviation":"NTKoo20"},{"id":"ahr-Deva-IN-ntaii20","version":"Ahirani  New Testament","description":"Ahirani: प्रेम संदेश (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Ahirani","code":"ahr","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Devanagari","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Chhotray Aind","copyright":"","localVersionName":"प्रेम संदेश","localVersionAbbreviation":"NTAii20"},{"id":"dso-ntsaa20","version":"Sida New Testament","description":"Desiya: ସତିଅର୍‌ ବାଟ୍‌ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Desiya","code":"dso","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Oriya","script":"Oriya","archivist":"Chhotray Aind","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ସତିଅର୍‌ ବାଟ୍‌","localVersionAbbreviation":"NTSaa20"},{"id":"juy-ntjaa20","version":"Juray Soura New Testament","description":"Juray: ଆଜାଡ଼ି ତଙରନ୍‌ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Juray","code":"juy","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Oriya","script":"Oriya","archivist":"Chhotray Aind","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ଆଜାଡ଼ି ତଙରନ୍‌","localVersionAbbreviation":"NTJaa20"},{"id":"unx-Orya-034-ntruu20","version":"Rimu: Munda New Testament","description":"Munda: ପାର୍‌ମେଶ୍ୱାର୍‌ଆଃ ଜୀନିଦ୍‌ ବାଚାନ୍‌ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Munda","code":"unx","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Oriya","script":"Oriya","archivist":"Chhotray Aind","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ପାର୍‌ମେଶ୍ୱାର୍‌ଆଃ ଜୀନିଦ୍‌ ବାଚାନ୍‌","localVersionAbbreviation":"NTRuu20"},{"id":"gaq-ntdaa20","version":"Dega: Gata Didayi New Testament","description":"Gata’: ସତ୍‌ ଗାଲି (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Gata’","code":"gaq","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Oriya","script":"Oriya","archivist":"Chhotray Aind","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ସତ୍‌ ଗାଲି","localVersionAbbreviation":"NTDaa20"},{"id":"kxv-Orya-IN-ntkii20","version":"Kuvi New Testament","description":"Kuvi: ପୁଃନି ମେ଼ରା (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Kuvi","code":"kxv","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Oriya","script":"Oriya","archivist":"Chhotray Aind","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ପୁଃନି ମେ଼ରା","localVersionAbbreviation":"NTKii20"},{"id":"peg-Orya-IN-ntnoo20","version":"Nepo: Pengo New Testament","description":"Pengo: ସତ୍‌ ବଚନ୍‌ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Pengo","code":"peg","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Oriya","script":"Oriya","archivist":"Chhotray Aind","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ସତ୍‌ ବଚନ୍‌","localVersionAbbreviation":"NTNoo20"},{"id":"vi-ovcb","version":"Biblica® Open Vietnamese Contemporary Bible 2015","description":"Vietnamese: Biblica® Thiên Ban Kinh Thánh Hiện Đại™ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Vietnamese","code":"vie","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Viet Nam","code":"VN"},"numeralSystem":"","script":"Code for inherited script","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Thiên Ban Kinh Thánh Hiện Đại™","localVersionAbbreviation":"OVCB"},{"id":"es-bes","version":"La Biblia en Español Sencillo","description":"The Holy Bible in simple Spanish","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Spanish","code":"spa","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Mexico","code":"MX"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"La Biblia en Español Sencillo","localVersionAbbreviation":"BES"},{"id":"rmc-зрб","version":"Carpathian Romani Bible","description":"Romani, Carpathian: Біблія про закарпатцько романо чіб (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Romani, Carpathian","code":"rmc","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Ukraine","code":"UA"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Cyrillic","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Біблія про закарпатцько романо чіб","localVersionAbbreviation":"ЗРБ"},{"id":"yom-onwm","version":"Biblica® Open Kiyombe Contemporary New Testament and Psalms 2002","description":"Yombe: Biblica® Open Nkanda wu Moyo, Nguizani Yimona ayi Minkunga 2002 (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Yombe","code":"yom","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Congo, the Democratic Republic of the","code":"CD"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Agatha John-Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Open Nkanda wu Moyo, Nguizani Yimona ayi Minkunga 2002","localVersionAbbreviation":"ONWM"},{"id":"en-bsb","version":"Berean Study Bible","description":"English: Berean Study Bible","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States of AmericaUnited Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern IrelandAustraliaCanadaAntigua and BarbudaBahamasBarbadosBelizeDominicaDominican RepublicAmerican SamoaGuamHaitiGuyanaIsraelIrelandJamaicaMaltaNew ZealandPhilippinesSaint Kitts and NevisSaint LuciaSaint Vincent and the GrenadinesTrinidad and TobagoNigeriaSouth Africa","code":"USGBAUCAAGBSBBBZDMDOASGUHTGYILIEJMMTNZPHKNLCVCTTNGZA"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Emma Canales","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Berean Study Bible","localVersionAbbreviation":"BSB"},{"id":"rmn-крб","version":"Crimean Romani Bible","description":"Romani, Balkan: Библия опэр крымски романи чиб (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Romani, Balkan","code":"rmn","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Ukraine","code":"UA"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Cyrillic","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Библия опэр крымски романи чиб","localVersionAbbreviation":"КРБ"},{"id":"rmy-UA-срб","version":"Servi Romani Bible","description":"Luke and Acts","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Romani, Vlax","code":"rmy","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Ukraine","code":"UA"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Cyrillic","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Библия пы сэрвицко ромско чиб","localVersionAbbreviation":"СРБ"},{"id":"nd-oben","version":"Biblica® Open Ndebele Contemporary Bible 2022","description":"Ndebele: Biblica® IBhayibhili Elingcwele LesiNdebele Elifinyelelekayo™ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Ndebele","code":"nde","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Zimbabwe","code":"ZW"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Njenga","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® IBhayibhili Elingcwele LesiNdebele Elifinyelelekayo™","localVersionAbbreviation":"OBEN"},{"id":"mdy-ጌኤ.ማፃ","version":"MAALE Bible","description":"Maale: MAALE Bible","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Male","code":"mdy","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"Ethiopia","code":"ET"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Ethiopic","archivist":"Emma Canales","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ጌኤዦ ማፃኣፖ","localVersionAbbreviation":"ጌኤ.ማፃ"},{"id":"de-DE-elbbk","version":"Elberfelder Translation (Version of bibelkommentare.de)","description":"Linguistically revised text of the Unrevised Elberfelder Translation with footnotes.","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"German, Standard","code":"deu","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Germany","code":"DE"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Johannes Runkel","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Elberfelder Übersetzung (Version von bibelkommentare.de)","localVersionAbbreviation":"ELBBK"},{"id":"kca-хб","version":"Khanty Bible","description":"Khanty: Хӑнты Перевод Библии (Portions)","scope":"Portions","language":{"name":"Khanty","code":"kca","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Russian Federation","code":"RU"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Cyrillic","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Хӑнты Перевод Библии","localVersionAbbreviation":"ХБ"},{"id":"tkr-Latn-AZ-tkr","version":"Tsakhur","description":"Tsakhur: Tsakhur (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Tsakhur","code":"tkr","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"AzerbaijanRussian Federation","code":"AZRU"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Tsakhur","localVersionAbbreviation":"TKR"},{"id":"tod-gdz","version":"Toma Bible","description":"Toma: GALA Daawoo Zɛʋɛi (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Toma","code":"tod","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Guinea","code":"GN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"GALA Daawoo Zɛʋɛi","localVersionAbbreviation":"GDZ"},{"id":"ig-biuo","version":"Biblica® Open Igbo Contemporary Bible 2020","description":"Igbo: Biblica® Baịbụlụ Nsọ nʼIgbo Ndị Ugbu a nke dịrị onye ọbụla ịgụ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Igbo","code":"ibo","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Nigeria","code":"NG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Baịbụlụ Nsọ nʼIgbo Ndị Ugbu a nke dịrị onye ọbụla ịgụ","localVersionAbbreviation":"BIUO"},{"id":"tw-wasna","version":"Biblica® Open Asante Twi Contemporary Bible 2020","description":"Twi: Biblica® Wɔnhia ɛho kwamma nwoma Asante Twi Nkwa Asɛm™ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Twi","code":"twi","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Ghana","code":"GH"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Wɔnhia ɛho kwamma nwoma Asante Twi Nkwa Asɛm™","localVersionAbbreviation":"WASNA"},{"id":"yo-oycb","version":"Biblica® Open Yoruba Contemporary Bible 2017","description":"Yoruba: Biblica® ní oore ọ̀fẹ́ láti lo Bíbélì Mímọ́ ní Èdè Yorùbá Òde-Òní (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Yoruba","code":"yor","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Nigeria","code":"NG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® ní oore ọ̀fẹ́ láti lo Bíbélì Mímọ́ ní Èdè Yorùbá Òde-Òní","localVersionAbbreviation":"OYCB"},{"id":"luo-onlt","version":"Biblica® Open New Luo Translation 2020","description":"Dholuo: Biblica® Ochiw Thuolo Motingʼo Loko Manyien™ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Dholuo","code":"luo","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Kenya","code":"KE"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Ochiw Thuolo Motingʼo Loko Manyien™","localVersionAbbreviation":"ONLT"},{"id":"tw-wakna","version":"Biblica® Open Akuapem Twi Contemporary Bible 2020","description":"Twi: Biblica® Wonhia ɛho kwamma nhoma Akuapem Twi Nkwa Asɛm™ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Twi","code":"twi","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Ghana","code":"GH"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Wonhia ɛho kwamma nhoma Akuapem Twi Nkwa Asɛm™","localVersionAbbreviation":"WAKNA"},{"id":"hu-neiv","version":"Biblica® Open Hungarian New Testament: Life, Truth and Light 2003","description":"Hungarian: Biblica® Nyitott Újszövetség: élet, igazság és világosság (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Hungarian","code":"hun","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Hungary","code":"HU"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Nyitott Újszövetség: élet, igazság és világosság","localVersionAbbreviation":"NEIV"},{"id":"fi-aeuut","version":"Biblica® Open Finnish Living News New Testament 1976","description":"Finnish: Biblica® Avoin Elävä uutinen: Uusi testamentti vapaasti kerrottuna (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Finnish","code":"fin","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Finland","code":"FI"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Avoin Elävä uutinen: Uusi testamentti vapaasti kerrottuna","localVersionAbbreviation":"AEUUT"},{"id":"nb-oelb","version":"Biblica® Open Norwegian Living New Testament 2005","description":"Norwegian Bokmål: Biblica® Open En Levende Bok: Det Nye Testamentet (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Norwegian Bokmål","code":"nob","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Norway","code":"NO"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Open En Levende Bok: Det Nye Testamentet","localVersionAbbreviation":"OELB"},{"id":"lg-olcb","version":"Biblica® Open Luganda Contemporary Bible 2014","description":"Ganda: Biblica® Bayibuli Entukuvu, Endagaano Enkadde nʼEndagaano Empya ekwatiddwa ku katambi™ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Ganda","code":"lug","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Uganda","code":"UG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Bayibuli Entukuvu, Endagaano Enkadde nʼEndagaano Empya ekwatiddwa ku katambi™","localVersionAbbreviation":"OLCB"},{"id":"ha-bsrk","version":"Biblica® Open Hausa Contemporary Bible 2020","description":"Hausa: Biblica® Buɗaɗɗen Littafi Mai Tsarki, Sabon Rai Don Kowa™ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Hausa","code":"hau","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Nigeria","code":"NG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Buɗaɗɗen Littafi Mai Tsarki, Sabon Rai Don Kowa™","localVersionAbbreviation":"BSRK"},{"id":"ny-tccl","version":"Biblica® Open Godʼs Word in Contemporary Chichewa","description":"Chichewa: Biblica® Tsekulani Mawu a Mulungu mu Chichewa Chalero (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Chichewa","code":"nya","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Malawi","code":"MW"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Tsekulani Mawu a Mulungu mu Chichewa Chalero","localVersionAbbreviation":"TCCl"},{"id":"ki-kgnk","version":"Biblica® Open Kikuyu Holy Word of God 2013","description":"Gikuyu: Biblica® Kiugo Gĩtheru Kĩa Ngai Kĩhingũre (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Gikuyu","code":"kik","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Kenya","code":"KE"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Kiugo Gĩtheru Kĩa Ngai Kĩhingũre","localVersionAbbreviation":"KGNK"},{"id":"pl-opsz","version":"Biblica® Open Polish Living New Testament 2016","description":"Polish: Biblica® Słowo Życia, otwarty dostęp (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Polish","code":"pol","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Poland","code":"PL"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Słowo Życia, otwarty dostęp","localVersionAbbreviation":"OPSZ"},{"id":"arb-kehm","version":"Biblica® Open New Arabic Version 2012","description":"Arabic, Standard: كتاب الحياة مجانى (Open New Arabic Version) (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Arabic, Standard","code":"arb","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"EgyptSaudi Arabia","code":"EGSA"},"numeralSystem":"Hindi","script":"Arabic","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Ketab El Hayat Majani/كتاب الحياة مجانى","localVersionAbbreviation":"KEHM"},{"id":"msc-Latn-011-fonipa-aks","version":"Sankaran Translation Project","description":"Sankaran is also know as Maninka of Faranah. Sankaran is the local name for the dialect","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Maninka, Sankaran","code":"msc","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Guinea","code":"GN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Alla la Kitabu Seniman","localVersionAbbreviation":"AKS"},{"id":"bhd-Deva-IN-bhdnt","version":"Bhadrawahi Bible","description":"Bible in Bhadrawahi Language (bhd)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Bhadrawahi","code":"bhd","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Hanok Kurian","copyright":"","localVersionName":"भड्लाई बाइबिल","localVersionAbbreviation":"BHDNT"},{"id":"msy-054-arubib20","version":"The Bible in Aruamu: Old Testament and New Testament","description":"Aruamu Bible","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Aruamu","code":"msy","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Papua New Guinea","code":"PG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Godɨn Eghaghanim: Akar Gavgavir Dɨkɨrɨzir Ghurim ko Igiam","localVersionAbbreviation":"AruBib20"},{"id":"rmy-врб","version":"Vlakh Romani Bible","description":"Eastern Vlakh Romani","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Romani, Vlax","code":"rmy","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Ukraine","code":"UA"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Cyrillic","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Библия пэ влахицко романи шыб","localVersionAbbreviation":"ВРБ"},{"id":"bht-Deva-IN-bhtnt","version":"Bhattiyali New Testament","description":"Bible in Bhattiyali language","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Bhattiyali","code":"bht","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Hanok Kurian","copyright":"","localVersionName":"भटियाली नोआ नियम","localVersionAbbreviation":"BHTNT"},{"id":"ckb-okss","version":"Biblica® Open Kurdi Sorani Standard Version 2020","description":"Kurdish, Central: Biblica® وەشانی بێبەرامبەری کوردیی سۆرانیی ستاندەر (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Kurdish, Central","code":"ckb","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Iraq","code":"IQ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Arabic","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® وەشانی بێبەرامبەری کوردیی سۆرانیی ستاندەر","localVersionAbbreviation":"OKSS"},{"id":"pt-BR-blt","version":"Biblia Livre Para Todos","description":"English translation with input from Hebrew and Greek","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Portuguese","code":"por","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Brazil","code":"BR"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Jonathan Gallagher","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblia Livre Para Todos","localVersionAbbreviation":"BLT"},{"id":"bwo-Latn-ET-brnntltn","version":"Borna New Testament Latin Version","description":"Handr Taara","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Borna","code":"bwo","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Ethiopia","code":"ET"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Dawit Asfaw","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Handr Taara","localVersionAbbreviation":"BrnNTLtn"},{"id":"mni-rsm","version":"Meitei: Roman Script 1st Translation","description":"Meitei: Meitei First Roman Script Bible Translation","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Meitei","code":"mni","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Suan Ngaihte","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ANOUBA WAREPNABA","localVersionAbbreviation":"RSM"},{"id":"is-olo","version":"Biblica® Open Icelandic Living New Testament and Psalms","description":"Icelandic: Biblica® Opna Lifandi Orð Nýja testamentið og Sálmarnir™ (New Testament+)","scope":"New Testament+","language":{"name":"Icelandic","code":"isl","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Iceland","code":"IS"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Opna Lifandi Orð Nýja testamentið og Sálmarnir™","localVersionAbbreviation":"OLO"},{"id":"hbo-wlc","version":"Westminister Leningrad Codex","description":"The Hebrew Bible, Westminister Leningrad Codex, with Strong's numbers","scope":"Old Testament","language":{"name":"Hebrew, Ancient","code":"hbo","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Israel","code":"IL"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Hebrew","archivist":"KMPJ","copyright":"","localVersionName":"כתבי הקודש","localVersionAbbreviation":"WLC"},{"id":"dao-dnt","version":"Dai-Chin: Bible Translation","description":"Dai Bible translation","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Chin, Daai","code":"dao","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"Myanmar","code":"MM"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Gladys Grasso","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Dai Cangcim Kthai","localVersionAbbreviation":"DNT"},{"id":"ta-IN-otcv","version":"Biblica® Open Indian Tamil Contemporary Version","description":"Biblica® திறந்தநிலை தமிழ் சமகால பதிப்பு","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Tamil","code":"tam","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Tamil","archivist":"Giju George","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® திறந்தநிலை தமிழ் சமகால பதிப்பு","localVersionAbbreviation":"OTCV"},{"id":"id-tsi","version":"Terjemahan Sederhana Indonesia","description":"Plain Indonesian Translation","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Indonesian","code":"ind","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"IndonesiaMalaysia","code":"IDMY"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Alkitab Terjemahan Sederhana Indonesia, Edisi Ketiga","localVersionAbbreviation":"TSI"},{"id":"kn-okcv","version":"Biblica® Open Kannada Contemporary Version 2022","description":"Biblica® ಉಚಿತ ಕನ್ನಡ ಸಮಕಾಲಿಕ ಭಾಷಾಂತರ™","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Kannada","code":"kan","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Kannada","archivist":"Prabhu Beelagi","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® ಉಚಿತ ಕನ್ನಡ ಸಮಕಾಲಿಕ ಭಾಷಾಂತರ","localVersionAbbreviation":"OKCV"},{"id":"ln-smnb","version":"Biblica® Open Lingala Contemporary Bible 2020","description":"Lingala: Biblica® Salela na bonsomi Mokanda na Bomoi (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Lingala","code":"lin","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Congo, the Democratic Republic of the","code":"CD"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Peggy Connett","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Salela na bonsomi Mokanda na Bomoi","localVersionAbbreviation":"SMNB"},{"id":"es-vbl","version":"Versión Biblia Libre","description":"Free Bible Version in Spanish","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Spanish","code":"spa","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"SpainMexicoParaguayColombiaChileEcuadorHondurasNicaraguaPeruPanamaCuba","code":"ESMXPYCOCLECHNNIPEPACU"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Jonathan Gallagher","copyright":"Versión 1.1 beta.Version 1.1 beta.","localVersionName":"Versión Biblia Libre","localVersionAbbreviation":"VBL"},{"id":"hi-IN-irvhin","version":"Indian Revised Version(IRV) Hindi - 2019","description":"Hindi: इंडियन रिवाइज्ड वर्जन (IRV) हिंदी - 2019 (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Hindi","code":"hin","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Vipin Bhadran","copyright":"","localVersionName":"इंडियन रिवाइज्ड वर्जन (IRV) हिंदी - 2019","localVersionAbbreviation":"IRVHin"},{"id":"as-irvasm","version":"Indian Revised Version (IRV) Assamese - 2019","description":"Assamese: ইণ্ডিয়ান ৰিভাইচ ভাৰচন (IRV) আচামিচ - 2019 (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Assamese","code":"asm","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Bengali","archivist":"Vipin Bhadran","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ইণ্ডিয়ান ৰিভাইচ ভাৰচন (IRV) আচামিচ - 2019","localVersionAbbreviation":"IRVAsm"},{"id":"mr-irvmar","version":"Indian Revised Version(IRV) Marathi - 2019","description":"Marathi: इंडियन रीवाइज्ड वर्जन (IRV) - मराठी (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Marathi","code":"mar","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Vipin Bhadran","copyright":"","localVersionName":"इंडियन रीवाइज्ड वर्जन (IRV) - मराठी","localVersionAbbreviation":"IRVMar"},{"id":"ta-irvtam","version":"Indian Revised Version (IRV) Tamil - 2019","description":"Tamil: இண்டியன் ரிவைஸ்டு வெர்ஸன் (IRV) - தமிழ் (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Tamil","code":"tam","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Tamil","archivist":"Vipin Bhadran","copyright":"","localVersionName":"இண்டியன் ரிவைஸ்டு வெர்ஸன் (IRV) - தமிழ்","localVersionAbbreviation":"IRVTam"},{"id":"ur-Deva-IN-irvurd","version":"Indian Revised Version (IRV) Urdu - 2019","description":"इंडियन रिवाइज्ड वर्जन (IRV) उर्दू - 2019","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Urdu","code":"urd","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Vipin Bhadran","copyright":"","localVersionName":"इंडियन रिवाइज्ड वर्जन (IRV) उर्दू - 2019","localVersionAbbreviation":"IRVUrd"},{"id":"bn-irvben","version":"Indian Revised Version (IRV) Bengali - 2019","description":"Bengali: ইন্ডিয়ান রিভাইজড ভার্সন (IRV) - বেঙ্গলী (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Bengali","code":"ben","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Bengali","archivist":"Vipin Bhadran","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ইন্ডিয়ান রিভাইজড ভার্সন (IRV) - বেঙ্গলী","localVersionAbbreviation":"IRVBen"},{"id":"kn-irvkan","version":"Indian Revised Version (IRV) Kannada - 2019","description":"Kannada: ಇಂಡಿಯನ್ ರಿವೈಜ್ಡ್ ವರ್ಸನ್ (IRV) - ಕನ್ನಡ - 2019 (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Kannada","code":"kan","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Kannada","archivist":"Vipin Bhadran","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ಇಂಡಿಯನ್ ರಿವೈಜ್ಡ್ ವರ್ಸನ್ (IRV) - ಕನ್ನಡ - 2019","localVersionAbbreviation":"IRVKan"},{"id":"ml-IN-irvmal","version":"Indian Revised Version (IRV) Malayalam - 2019","description":"Malayalam: Indian Revised Version in Malayalam (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Malayalam","code":"mal","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Malayalam","archivist":"Vipin Bhadran","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Indian Revised Version in Malayalam","localVersionAbbreviation":"IRVMAL"},{"id":"te-IN-irvtel","version":"Indian Revised Version (IRV) Telugu - 2019","description":"Telugu: ఇండియన్ రివైజ్డ్ వెర్షన్ (IRV) - తెలుగు -2019 (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Telugu","code":"tel","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Telugu","archivist":"Vipin Bhadran","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ఇండియన్ రివైజ్డ్ వెర్షన్ (IRV) - తెలుగు -2019","localVersionAbbreviation":"IRVTel"},{"id":"ory-irvory","version":"Indian Revised Version(IRV) Odia - 2021","description":"Oriya: ଇଣ୍ଡିୟାନ ରିୱାଇସ୍ଡ୍ ୱରସନ୍ ଓଡିଆ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Oriya","code":"ory","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Oriya","archivist":"Vipin Bhadran","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ଇଣ୍ଡିୟାନ ରିୱାଇସ୍ଡ୍ ୱରସନ୍ ଓଡିଆ","localVersionAbbreviation":"IRVOry"},{"id":"gu-irvguj","version":"Indian Revised Version (IRV) Gujarati-2019","description":"Gujarati: ઇન્ડિયન રીવાઇઝ્ડ વર્ઝન ગુજરાતી - 2019 (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Gujarati","code":"guj","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Gujarati","archivist":"Vipin Bhadran","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ઇન્ડિયન રીવાઇઝ્ડ વર્ઝન ગુજરાતી - 2019","localVersionAbbreviation":"IRVGuj"},{"id":"pa-IN-irvpun","version":"Indian Revised Version (IRV) Punjabi - 2019","description":"Punjabi: ਇੰਡਿਅਨ ਰਿਵਾਇਜ਼ਡ ਵਰਜ਼ਨ (IRV) - ਪੰਜਾਬੀ","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Panjabi, Eastern","code":"pan","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Gurmukhi","archivist":"Vipin Bhadran","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ਇੰਡਿਅਨ ਰਿਵਾਇਜ਼ਡ ਵਰਜ਼ਨ (IRV) - ਪੰਜਾਬੀ","localVersionAbbreviation":"IRVPun"},{"id":"arp-arp","version":"Arapaho Luke","description":"Luke in the Arapaho language of the United States of America","scope":"Portions","language":{"name":"Arapaho","code":"arp","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States of America","code":"US"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Hethadenee waunauyaunee vadan Luke Vanenāna","localVersionAbbreviation":"ARP"},{"id":"kpg-kpg","version":"Kapingamarangi Bible","description":"The Holy Bible in the Kapingamarangi language of the Federated States of Micronesia, spoken on the Kapingamarangi and Ponape Islands, Caroline Islands","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Kapingamarangi","code":"kpg","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Micronesia, Federated States of","code":"FM"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Beeba Dabu","localVersionAbbreviation":"KPG"},{"id":"nho-nho","version":"Takuu New Testament","description":"The New Testament in the Takuu language of North Solomons Province, Papua New Guinea","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Takuu","code":"nho","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Papua New Guinea","code":"PG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Na Taratara TeAtua i naa taratara Takuu","localVersionAbbreviation":"NHO"},{"id":"th-kjv","version":"Thai KJV","description":"The Holy Bible in Thai, translated from the English KJV","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Thai","code":"tha","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Thailand","code":"TH"},"numeralSystem":"Thai","script":"Thai","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"พระคัมภีร์ภาษาไทยฉบับ KJV","localVersionAbbreviation":"KJV"},{"id":"bsp-kkk","version":"Baga Translation Unicode","description":"Baga Sitemu: Kitabu ka Kanu (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Baga Sitemu","code":"bsp","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Guinea","code":"GN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Melva Buhrer","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Kitabu ka Kanu","localVersionAbbreviation":"KKK"},{"id":"sn-bdrsc","version":"Biblica® Open Shona Contemporary Bible 2017","description":"Shona: Biblica® Bhaibheri Dzvene Rakasununguka MuChiShona Chanhasi 2017 (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Shona","code":"sna","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Zimbabwe","code":"ZW"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Bhaibheri Dzvene Rakasununguka MuChiShona Chanhasi 2017","localVersionAbbreviation":"BDRSC"},{"id":"quc-k’iche’","version":"Nuevo Testamento K'iche' of Totonicapan","description":"K’iche’: RI KꞌAKꞌ TESTAMENTO PA TZIJOBꞌAL KꞌICHEꞌ (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"K’iche’","code":"quc","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Guatemala","code":"GT"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"RI KꞌAKꞌ TESTAMENTO PA TZIJOBꞌAL KꞌICHEꞌ","localVersionAbbreviation":"K’iche’"},{"id":"sus-soso","version":"Susu Translation","description":"Susu: Soso Kitaabuie: Tawureta, Yabura, Inyila (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Susu","code":"sus","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Guinea","code":"GN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Melva Buhrer","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Soso Kitaabuie: Tawureta, Yabura, Inyila","localVersionAbbreviation":"Soso"},{"id":"sus-Arab-susu","version":"Susu Arabic","description":"Susu: Ala xa Kitaabui Sosoe bɛ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Susu","code":"sus","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Guinea","code":"GN"},"numeralSystem":"","script":"Arabic","archivist":"Melva Buhrer","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Ala xa Kitaabui Sosoe bɛ","localVersionAbbreviation":"Susu"},{"id":"yal-yalunka","version":"Yalunka Bible","description":"Yalunka: Kisin Kiraan Kitabuna (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Yalunka","code":"yal","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"GuineaSierra Leone","code":"GNSL"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Melva Buhrer","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Kisin Kiraan Kitabuna","localVersionAbbreviation":"Yalunka"},{"id":"bn-obss","version":"Biblica® Open Bengali Contemporary Version 2019","description":"Bengali: Biblica® মুক্তভাবে বাংলা সমকালীন সংস্করণের (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Bengali","code":"ben","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Bengali","archivist":"Prabhu Beelagi","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® মুক্তভাবে বাংলা সমকালীন সংস্করণের","localVersionAbbreviation":"OBSS"},{"id":"hi-ohss","version":"Biblica® Open Hindi Contemporary Version 2019","description":"Hindi: Biblica® हिंदी समकालीन संस्करण-स्वतंत्र उपलब्धि (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Hindi","code":"hin","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Giju George","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® हिंदी समकालीन संस्करण-स्वतंत्र उपलब्धि","localVersionAbbreviation":"OHSS"},{"id":"ur-Deva-urdgvh","version":"Urdu Geo Version (Hindi Script)","description":"The Holy Bible in the Urdu Language, Urdu Geo Version, Hindi Script","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Urdu","code":"urd","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Pakistan","code":"PK"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Devanagari","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"किताबे-मुक़द्दस","localVersionAbbreviation":"URDGVH"},{"id":"ur-Latn-ugv","version":"Urdu Geo Version (Roman Script)","description":"The Holy Bible in Urdu, Urdu Geo Version, Roman Script","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Urdu","code":"urd","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Pakistan","code":"PK"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Kitab-i Muqaddas","localVersionAbbreviation":"UGV"},{"id":"swh-onen","version":"Biblica® Open Kiswahili Contemporary Version (Neno) 2015","description":"Swahili: Biblica® Toleo Wazi la Neno: Biblia Takatifu™ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Swahili","code":"swh","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"KenyaTanzania, United Republic of","code":"KETZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Toleo Wazi la Neno: Biblia Takatifu™","localVersionAbbreviation":"ONEN"},{"id":"nag-isvnag","version":"Indian Standard Version (ISV) Nagamese","description":"Naga Pidgin: Indian Standard Version (ISV) Nagamese (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Naga Pidgin","code":"nag","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Vipin Bhadran","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Indian Standard Version (ISV) Nagamese","localVersionAbbreviation":"ISVNag"},{"id":"ur-Aran-urdgvu","version":"Urdu Geo Version (Urdu Script)","description":"The Holy Bible in Urdu, Urdu Script","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Urdu","code":"urd","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"PakistanIndia","code":"PKIN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Code for uncoded script","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"کتابِ مقدّس","localVersionAbbreviation":"URDGVU"},{"id":"bla-Latn-019-bla","version":"Blackfoot Gospel of Matthew [bla] Canada","description":"The Gospel of Matthew in the Blackfoot language of Canada","scope":"Portions","language":{"name":"Siksika","code":"bla","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Canada","code":"CA"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"ŎKHS' I TSĬN IK SĬN NI ST. MATTHEW OT SĬN AI PI.","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"zaj-kizalamo","version":"Zaramo New Testament","description":"Zaramo New Testament","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Zaramo","code":"zaj","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania, United Republic of","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Lagano da Isambi da Mndewa na Mkombola Wetu Yesu Kilisto","localVersionAbbreviation":"Kizalamo"},{"id":"sv-skb","version":"Svenska Kärnbibeln","description":"Swedish: Svenska Kärnbibeln - en expanderad översättning (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Swedish","code":"swe","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Sweden","code":"SE"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Jonas Bergsten","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Svenska Kärnbibeln - en expanderad översättning","localVersionAbbreviation":"skb"},{"id":"en-webus","version":"World English Bible USA without Strong's numbers","description":"The same as engWEB14, but with the Strong's numbers stripped out","scope":"Bible with Deuterocanon","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States of AmericaCanada","code":"USCA"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"KMPJ","copyright":"","localVersionName":"World English Bible, American English Edition, without Strong's numbers","localVersionAbbreviation":"WEBUS"},{"id":"en-web","version":"World English Bible (American Edition)","description":"Related dialect adaptation of the American Standard Version of 1901 into modern English","scope":"Bible with Deuterocanon","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States of America","code":"US"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"KMPJ","copyright":"","localVersionName":"World English Bible","localVersionAbbreviation":"WEB"},{"id":"geb-kirnt","version":"Kire NT for DBL","description":"Kire New Testament","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Kire","code":"geb","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Papua New Guinea","code":"PG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Fhe Bakɨmen Kaman Kameŋ","localVersionAbbreviation":"KirNT"},{"id":"en-webbe","version":"World English Bible British Edition","description":"British/International spelling edition of the World English Bible","scope":"Bible with Deuterocanon","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland","code":"GB"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"KMPJ","copyright":"PUBLIC DOMAIN","localVersionName":"World English Bible British Edition","localVersionAbbreviation":"WEBBE"},{"id":"kql-kbnt","version":"Kianying Balang Mark for DBL","description":"Gospel of Mark in the Kianying Balang (Kyenele) Language)","scope":"Portions","language":{"name":"Kyenele","code":"kql","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Papua New Guinea","code":"PG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Mak - Kiañiŋ Balaŋ","localVersionAbbreviation":"KBNT"},{"id":"rmy-лрб","version":"Lovari Romani Bible","description":"Romani, Vlax: Библия пэ ловарицко романы щиб (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Romani, Vlax","code":"rmy","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Ukraine","code":"UA"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Cyrillic","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Библия пэ ловарицко романы щиб","localVersionAbbreviation":"ЛРБ"},{"id":"en-wmb","version":"World Messianic Bible (American English)","description":"Modern English Bible for Messianic Jews","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States of America","code":"US"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"KMPJ","copyright":"PUBLIC DOMAIN","localVersionName":"World Messianic Bible","localVersionAbbreviation":"WMB"},{"id":"en-wmbbe","version":"World Messianic Bible British Edition","description":"A translation of the Holy Bible for Messianic Jews who use British/International English","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"AustraliaAmerican SamoaBahamasBelizeBritish Indian Ocean TerritoryVirgin Islands, BritishCanadaKenyaMicronesia, Federated States ofNew ZealandPapua New GuineaSamoaSingaporeTongaUnited Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland","code":"AUASBSBZIOVGCAKEFMNZPGWSSGTOGB"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"KMPJ","copyright":"PUBLIC DOMAIN","localVersionName":"World Messianic Bible British Edition","localVersionAbbreviation":"WMBBE"},{"id":"ena-apalgent","version":"Apal NT, Gen, Exo for DBL","description":"Genesis, Exodus and the New Testament in Apal","scope":"New Testament+","language":{"name":"Apali","code":"ena","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Papua New Guinea","code":"PG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Asɨ dɨ manasɨŋ","localVersionAbbreviation":"ApalGENT"},{"id":"ml-omcv","version":"Biblica® Open Malayalam Contemporary Version 2020","description":"Malayalam: Biblica® സ്വതന്ത്രം സമകാലിക മലയാളവിവർത്തനം (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Malayalam","code":"mal","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Malayalam","archivist":"Prabhu Beelagi","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® സ്വതന്ത്രം സമകാലിക മലയാളവിവർത്തനം","localVersionAbbreviation":"OMCV"},{"id":"kqa-mummat","version":"Mum NT Portions for DBL","description":"NT Portions in Mum","scope":"Portions","language":{"name":"Mum","code":"kqa","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Papua New Guinea","code":"PG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Kuyu Avi Matyu Yɨhimbɨvɨrami","localVersionAbbreviation":"MumMat"},{"id":"msy-arunt04","version":"Aruamu New Testament [msy] Papua New Guinea 2004 DBL","description":"New Testament in the Aruamu Language for DBL","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Aruamu","code":"msy","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Papua New Guinea","code":"PG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Godɨn Akar Aghuim; Akar Dɨkɨrɨzir Gavgavir Igiam","localVersionAbbreviation":"AruNT04"},{"id":"taw-taynt","version":"Tay NT for DBL","description":"Tay New Testament","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Tai","code":"taw","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Papua New Guinea","code":"PG"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Jisas Klays Takaw Teplep Ne","localVersionAbbreviation":"TayNT"},{"id":"rmy-gsp","version":"Gurbet Bible","description":"Romani, Vlax: E Devleso Lafi ki Gurbetsko dijalekt (New Testament+)","scope":"New Testament+","language":{"name":"Romani, Vlax","code":"rmy","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Serbia","code":"RS"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Michal Becvar","copyright":"","localVersionName":"E Devleso Lafi ki Gurbetsko dijalekt","localVersionAbbreviation":"GSP"},{"id":"omb-wstmv","version":"Havai","description":"Ambae, East: Waratau Siaga Tatuei mo Vilegi (Old Testament)","scope":"Old Testament","language":{"name":"Ambae, East","code":"omb","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Vanuatu","code":"VU"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"PBT Archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Waratau Siaga Tatuei mo Vilegi","localVersionAbbreviation":"WSTmV"},{"id":"vi-vie","version":"Vietnamese Bible 1925 [vie] Vietnam","description":"The Holy Bible in Vietnamese, 1925 translation","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Vietnamese","code":"vie","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Viet Nam","code":"VN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Kinh Thánh","localVersionAbbreviation":"VIE"},{"id":"ekk-pkp","version":"Piibel Kõigile","description":"Estonian, Standard: Piibel Kõigile (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Estonian, Standard","code":"ekk","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Estonia","code":"EE"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Jonathan Gallagher","copyright":"Sihtasutus Piibel Kõigile. Released under Creative Commons Version 4 BY-SA","localVersionName":"Piibel Kõigile","localVersionAbbreviation":"PKP"},{"id":"bgg-bug","version":"Bugun: Bible Translation 1st Edition","description":"Bugun first Bible translation","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Bugun","code":"bgg","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Suan Ngaihte","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Iwo Surua Mua Wie Pha Bible","localVersionAbbreviation":"BUG"},{"id":"sch-sak","version":"Sakachep: Bible Translation 1st Edition","description":"Sakachep first Bible translation","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Sakachep","code":"sch","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Suan Ngaihte","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Pathien Lekhabu Inthieng Chongtung Thar","localVersionAbbreviation":"SAK"},{"id":"rmy-Latn-039-x-vwa-rab","version":"Arli (Western) New Testament","description":"Western Slavic Arli","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Romani, Vlax","code":"rmy","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"SerbiaCroatiaBosnia and HerzegovinaMontenegroNorth Macedonia","code":"RSHRBAMEMK"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Sergej Radosevic","copyright":"","localVersionName":"I Biblija ki Arli romani čhib","localVersionAbbreviation":"RAB"},{"id":"kfw-khmnt","version":"Kharam: Bible Translation 1st Edition, The NT in Kharam","description":"Naga, Kharam: First Naga, The New Testament in Kharam","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Naga, Kharam","code":"kfw","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"India","code":"IN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Suan Ngaihte","copyright":"","localVersionName":"The New Testament in Kharam","localVersionAbbreviation":"KHMNT"},{"id":"rmy-Latn-039-x-vc-rčb","version":"Chergash New Testament","description":"Serby Romani dialect","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Romani, Vlax","code":"rmy","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"SerbiaCroatiaBosnia and Herzegovina","code":"RSHRBA"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Sergej Radosevic","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblija pe romani Čergarsko čhib","localVersionAbbreviation":"RČB"},{"id":"en-kjv","version":"King James Version [eng] without Strong's numbers, 1769 standardized text","description":"English: King James Version of the Holy Bible (Bible with Deuterocanon)","scope":"Bible with Deuterocanon","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland","code":"GB"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"KMPJ","copyright":"PUBLIC DOMAIN","localVersionName":"King James Version of the Holy Bible","localVersionAbbreviation":"KJV"},{"id":"ziw-Latn-TZ-zibt","version":"The New Testament in Zigua","description":"Zigua","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Zigua","code":"ziw","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Roman","archivist":"Kees de Blois -archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Lagano hya","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"ndj-Latn-TZ-ndbv","version":"The New Testament in Ndamba","description":"Ndamba New Testament","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Ndamba","code":"ndj","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Roman","archivist":"Kees de Blois -archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Lilaghanu lya shonu","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"ngp-ngbv","version":"Nguu New Testament","description":"Nguu New Testament","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Nguu","code":"ngp","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Roman","archivist":"Kees de Blois -archivist","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Ndagano mp'ya kwa wanth'u wose","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"poy-pbv","version":"The New Testament in Pogoro","description":"The New Testament in Pogoro","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Shipogoro","code":"poy","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Roman","archivist":"Melva Wahl","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Lipatanu Lya Syayi Kwa Wantu Woseri","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"kdc-kutu","version":"The New Testament in Kutu","description":"The New Testament in Kutu","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Kutu","code":"kdc","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Roman","archivist":"Melva Wahl","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Lagano da Sambi kwa Wanhu Wose","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"ruf-lbv","version":"The New Testament in Lughuru","description":"The New Testament in Lughuru","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Chilughuru","code":"ruf","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Roman","archivist":"Melva Wahl","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Laghano Lya Sambi Kwe Iwanu Wose","localVersionAbbreviation":""},{"id":"mgh-mnt","version":"Makua New Testament 2015","description":"Makhuwa-Meetto: Makua New Testament 2015 New Testament","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Makhuwa-Meetto","code":"mgh","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"Tanzania","code":"TZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Gladys Grasso","copyright":"","localVersionName":"The Word for the World International","localVersionAbbreviation":"MNT"},{"id":"he-hdzp","version":"heOHD09","description":"Hebrew, Modern: Biblica®‎ ‫הברית החדשה/הדרך זכויות פתוחות (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Hebrew, Modern","code":"heb","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Israel","code":"IL"},"numeralSystem":"Hebrew","script":"Hebrew","archivist":"Kent Spielmann","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica®‎ ‫הברית החדשה/הדרך זכויות פתוחות","localVersionAbbreviation":"HDZP"},{"id":"en-tcent","version":"The Text-Critical English New Testament","description":"English: Text-Critical English New Testament (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States of America","code":"US"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Text-Critical English New Testament","localVersionAbbreviation":"TCENT"},{"id":"grc-tcgnt","version":"The Text-Critical Greek New Testament","description":"Greek, Ancient: Text-Critical Greek Majority Text (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Greek, Ancient","code":"grc","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Greece","code":"GR"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Greek","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Text-Critical Greek Majority Text","localVersionAbbreviation":"TCGNT"},{"id":"ee-oal","version":"eweOAL20","description":"Ewe: Biblica® Se aɖeke mebla Biblia zazã o Agbenya La™ (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Ewe","code":"ewe","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Ghana","code":"GH"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Bob Wood","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Se aɖeke mebla Biblia zazã o Agbenya La™","localVersionAbbreviation":"OAL"},{"id":"en-US-asvbt","version":"American Standard Version (Byzantine Text with Apocrypha)","description":"English: American Standard Version Byzantine Text with Apocrypha (Bible with Deuterocanon)","scope":"Bible with Deuterocanon","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common - Literary"},"country":{"name":"United States of America","code":"US"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"","localVersionName":"American Standard Version Byzantine Text with Apocrypha","localVersionAbbreviation":"ASVBT"},{"id":"en-asv","version":"American Standard Version of 1901 [eng] ASV","description":"Adaptation of the English Revised Version of 1895 into American English","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"English","code":"eng","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"United States of America","code":"US"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Kahunapule Michael Johnson","copyright":"PUBLIC DOMAIN","localVersionName":"American Standard Version of the Holy Bible","localVersionAbbreviation":"ASV"},{"id":"cmn-Hans-CN-feb","version":"免费的易读圣经 Free Easy-to-read Bible","description":"Chinese, Mandarin: 免费的易读圣经 Free Easy-to-read Bible (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Chinese, Mandarin","code":"cmn","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"China","code":"CN"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Han (Simplified variant)","archivist":"Jonathan Gallagher","copyright":"Version 1.0.","localVersionName":"免费的易读圣经 Free Easy-to-read Bible","localVersionAbbreviation":"FEB"},{"id":"be-ббб","version":"Bible (A.Bokun translation)","description":"Bible in belarusian translated by A.Bokun","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Belarusan","code":"bel","level":"Common"},"country":{"name":"Belarus","code":"BY"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Cyrillic","archivist":"Emma Canales","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Біблія (пераклад А.Бокуна)","localVersionAbbreviation":"БББ"},{"id":"hr-okok","version":"Biblica® Open Croatian New Testament","description":"Croatian: Biblica® Open Knjiga O Kristu (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Croatian","code":"hrv","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Croatia","code":"HR"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Open Knjiga O Kristu","localVersionAbbreviation":"OKOK"},{"id":"cs-osnc","version":"Biblica® Open Slovo na cestu (Czech Living New Testament)","description":"Czech: Biblica® Open Slovo na cestu (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Czech","code":"ces","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Czechia","code":"CZ"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Peggy Connett","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Open Slovo na cestu","localVersionAbbreviation":"OSNC"},{"id":"tn-olef","version":"Biblica® Open Tswana Living New Testament","description":"Tswana: Biblica® Open Lefoko: La Botshelo Kgolagano e Ntsha (New Testament)","scope":"New Testament","language":{"name":"Tswana","code":"tsn","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Botswana","code":"BW"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"John Dunham","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Biblica® Open Lefoko: La Botshelo Kgolagano e Ntsha","localVersionAbbreviation":"OLEF"},{"id":"gaz-habh","version":"Biblica® Open New Oromo Contemporary Version 2022","description":"Oromo, West Central: Kitaaba Qulqulluu, Hiikkaa Ammayyaa Banamaa Haaraa, Loqoda Dhiʼaa (Bible)","scope":"Bible","language":{"name":"Oromo, West Central","code":"gaz","level":"Basic"},"country":{"name":"Ethiopia","code":"ET"},"numeralSystem":"Arabic","script":"Latin","archivist":"Agatha John-Thomas","copyright":"","localVersionName":"Kitaaba Qulqulluu, Hiikkaa Ammayyaa Banamaa Haaraa, Loqoda Dhiʼaa","localVersionAbbreviation":"HABH"}]